In our time, no foreign army has ever occupied American soil. Until now.
Red Dawn is a action, thriller, war film directed by John Milius.
It is the dawn of World War III.
In mid-western America, a group of teenagers band together to defend
their town—and their country—from invading Soviet forces.
Jed, played by Patrick Swayze.
Matt, played by Charlie Sheen.
Robert, played by C. Thomas Howell.
Erica, played by Lea Thompson.
Daryl, played by Darren Dalton.
Toni, played by Jennifer Grey.
Red Dawn is a 1984 American action drama film directed by John Milius, from a screenplay
co-written with Kevin Reynolds, and starring Patrick Swayze, Charlie Sheen, C.
Thomas Howell, Lea Thompson and Jennifer Grey, with supporting roles played by Ben Johnson,
Darren Dalton, Harry Dean Stanton, Ron O'Neal, William Smith and Powers Boothe.
Set during a fictional World War III between an increasingly isolated United States and the Soviet Union, the film follows a group of
teenage guerrillas, known as the Wolverines, fighting against a Soviet-backed Latin American invasion force in Colorado.
Despite mixed reviews from critics, the film became a commercial
success, grossing $38 million against a budget of $17 million.
It was the first film to be released in the United States with a PG-13 rating
under the modified rating system introduced on July 1, 1984.
A remake was released in 2012.
The film explores themes of guerrilla warfare,
future, fight, colorado, invasion.
The tone is emotional and intense.